[{"question":"DNA Is _____ stranded structure ","a":"Single ","b":"Double ","c":"Triple ","d":"None of these ","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"If one strand of DNA has the sequence ATGCTTGA, the sequence in the complimentary strand would be","a":"TCCGAACT","b":"TACGTAGT","c":"TACGAACT","d":"TAGCTAGT","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"DNA and RNA contain four bases each. Which of following bases is not present in RNA?","a":"Adenine","b":"Uracil","c":"Thymine","d":"Cytosine","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"A sequence of how many nucleotides in messenger RNA makes a codon for an amino acid? ","a":"Three","b":"Four","c":"One","d":"Two","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The process by which synthesis of protein takes place based on the genetic information present in m-RNA is called ","a":"Translation","b":"Transcription","c":"Replication","d":"Messenger hypothesis","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The chemical change in DNA molecule that could lead to synthesis of protein with an altered amino acid sequence is called","a":"replication","b":"lipid formation","c":"cellular membrane","d":"mutation","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Accumulation of which of the following molecules in the muscles occurs as a result of vigorous exercise?","a":"Glycogen","b":"Glucose","c":"Pyruvic acid","d":"L-lactic acid","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The non-essential amino acid among the following is:","a":"valine","b":"leucine","c":"alanine","d":"lysine","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following compounds can form a zwitterion?","a":"Aniline","b":"Acetanilide","c":"Glycine","d":"Benzoic acid","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Invert sugar is","a":"chemically inactive form of sugar","b":"equimolecular mixture of glucose and fructose","c":"mixture of glucose and sucrose","d":"a variety of cane sugar","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Glucose molecule reacts with 'X' number of molecules of phenylhydrazine to vield osazone. The value of 'X' is","a":"four","b":"one","c":"two","d":"three","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The helical structure of protein is stabilized by","a":"dipeptide bonds","b":"hydrogen bonds","c":"ether bonds","d":"peptide bonds","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following reactions of glucose Explained can be only by its cyclic structure? ","a":"Glucose forms pentaacetate","b":"Glucose reacts with hydroxylamine to form an oxime","c":"Pentaacetate of glucose does not react with hydroxyl amine","d":"Glucose is oxidised by nitric acid to gluconic acid","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following indicates the order in which amino acids are linked together in a protein?","a":"Primary structure","b":"Secondary structure","c":"Tertiary structure","d":"Quaternary structure","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following terms indicates to the arrangement of different protein subunits in a multiprotein complex ?","a":"Primary structure","b":"Secondary structure","c":"Tertiary structure","d":"Quaternary structure","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Secondary structure of protein is mainly governed by","a":"hydrogen bonds","b":"covalent bonds","c":"ionic bonds","d":"disulphide bonds","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The secondary structure of a protein refers to","a":"fixed configuration of the polypeptide backbone","b":"a helical backbone","c":"hydrophobic interactions","d":"sequence of a-amino acids","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Coagulation of protein is known as","a":"dehydration","b":"decay","c":"deamination","d":"denaturing","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following terms refers to the overall three dimensional shape of a protein.","a":"Primary structure","b":"Secondary structure","c":"Tertiary structure","d":"Quaternary structure","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following indicates to 'regions of ordered  structure within a protein\".","a":"Primary structure","b":"Secondary structure","c":"Tertiary structure","d":"Quaternary structure","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The presence or absence of hydroxyl group on which carbon atom of sugar differentiates RNA and DNA?","a":"1st","b":"2nd","c":"3rd","d":"4th","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"In DNA the linkages between different nitrogenous bases are:","a":"peptide linkage","b":"phosphate linkage","c":"H-bonding","d":"glycosidic linkage","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"DNA multiplication is called as","a":"translation","b":"transduction","c":"transcription","d":"replication","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The double helical structure of DNA was proposed by","a":"Watson and Crick","b":"Meichers","c":"Emil Fischer","d":"Khorana","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Cellular oxidation of glucose is a:","a":"spontaneous and endothermic process","b":"non spontaneous and exothermic process","c":"non spontaneous and endothermic process","d":"spontaneous and exothermic process","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"What is the efficiency of glucose metabolism if 1 mole of glucose gives 38ATP energy? (Given: The enthalpy of combustion of glucose is 686 kcal, IATP-7.3kcal)","a":"100%","b":"38%","c":"62%","d":"80%","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Purines present in DNA are:","a":"adenine and thymine","b":"guanine and thymine","c":"cytosine and thymine","d":"adenine and guanine","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"DNA molecule Has _____ internucleotide linkage and  _____sequence of the different nucleotides.","a":"regular, regular","b":"regular, irregular","c":"irregular, regular","d":"irregular, irregular","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"DNA has a _____ backbone.","a":"phosphate-purine","b":"pyrimidines-sugar","c":"phosphate-sugar","d":"purine-pyrimidine","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Out of the four different kinds of nitrogenous bases which are commonly found in DNA. has been Replaced _____ in some organisms.","a":"adenine","b":"guanine","c":"cytosine","d":"thymine","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"All monosaccharides are reducing sugars.","a":"True","b":"False","c":"May be","d":"Don't know ","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"DNA Yields _____ a Base on a complete hydrolysis.","a":"Pentose sugar","b":"Phosphoric acid","c":"Both (Pentose Sugar) And( Phosphoric Acid)","d":"None of these ","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"When the number of amino acids is more than ten, then the product called","a":"Polypeptide","b":"Peptide","c":"Gluconic acid","d":"Aldose","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Five membered cyclic structure of glucose is called ","a":"Primary structure ","b":"Secondary structure ","c":"Quantride structure ","d":"pyranose structure.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Five membered cyclic structure of glucose is Called pyranose structure ","a":"True","b":"False","c":"May be","d":"Don't know ","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The cyclic structure of glucose is correctly represented by","a":"Primary structure ","b":"Secondary structure ","c":"pyranose structure.","d":"Haworth structure.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"DNA Yields _____,_____ and based on a complete hydrolysis.","a":"Phosphoric Acid ","b":"Pentose sugar","c":"Gluconic acid ","d":"Both (Phosphoric Acid ) ,(Pentose Sugar)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"A tripeptide contains _____Amino Acid Linked By_____ peptide linkage ","a":"One , three","b":"Three, two ","c":"Two, three","d":"One, one","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"During denaturation,  _____  structures of proteins are destroyed.","a":"Secondary","b":"Tertiary","c":"Both (Secondary) and (Tertiary)","d":"None of these ","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The linkage that connect c-amino acid together is known as","a":"Peptide linkage ","b":"Polypeptide linkage ","c":"Aldose linkage ","d":"Pentose linkage ","hint":"","correct":"a"}]